Srinivasan Chakkarapani

Digital Product Designer (UI-UX)

www.srinivasan.design +1 312-973-6557 tcsreeni93@gmail.com

Summary

A Passionate full spectrum product designer with 3 years of experience designing and shipping digital products for multiple companies from Food Tech, Fintech & SaaS. I'm an advocate for functional, aesthetic and user centered products which has an impact on people's life solving a need. I have a strong belief that a good product is a concoction of design and technology.

Education

Master of Science Human Computer Interaction DePaul University, Chicago - May 2020 (Expected)

Bachelor of Technology Computer Science & Engineering SASTRA University, India - May 2015

Professional Experience

Interaction Designer, Zeta

February 2018 - August 2018

Worked as an interaction designer for two stealth mode web products bundled inside the Zeta Optima product which focuses on digitising the tax benefits of employees. Intiated & framed a design system for products across web and mobile platforms which helped the team.

Product Designer, Zoho Corporation

December 2015 - January 2018

Designed and shipped the Zoho Sheet product as the primary product designer. As a principle designer, I worked on the application's mobile platforms (i.e.) iOS, Android from ideating features, wireframing to setting visual standards and framing a design system. Worked Closely with the developers, Product managers to effectively ship the product to the respective application stores which onboarded multiple web users on mobile platforms.

Product Designer, Holachef

June 2015 - December 2015

Designed the iOS and Android Application for the company. Also wore the hat of web designer in designing the primary web product. Also helped in designing various back end applications that helped in the functioning of the business.

Key Skills

Information Architecture

Contextual Inquiry

Wireframing

Interaction Design

Visual Design

Prototyping

Motion Design

Usablity Testing

Design Systems

Mobile Design

Web Design

User Interviews

Low/ High fidelity mockups

Competitive Analysis

Tools

Wireframing

Balsamiq, Axure RP

Design

Sketch, Adobe Photoshop & Illustrator, XD, Figma.

Prototyping

Principle, Adobe After Effects, Framer X, Marvel, Invision.

Languages

HTML, CSS, Javascript.